git init      - Initialize a new Git repository
git clone     - Copy a remote repository to local system
git add       - Stage files to prepare for commit
git commit    - Save staged changes permanently
git status    - Show current status of working directory
git log       - Show commit history
git branch    - List, create, or delete branches
git checkout  - Switch branches
git merge     - Merge changes from another branch
git push      - Upload local commits to GitHub
